Finding Aid for the United States v. Anthony Joseph Russo and Daniel Ellsberg Transcripts, 1972-1973 LSC.2017
UCLA Library Special Collections
United States v. Anthony Joseph Russo and Daniel Ellsberg Transcripts
1972-1973
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2017
22 Linear Feet (44 boxes)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942339103606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of pre-trial proceedings, the complete trial transcript, legal files relating to motions, exhibit materials, witness books, press files, clippings, biographical material, and photographs.
Legal documents.; Security classification (Government documents) -- United States.; Ellsberg, Daniel; Russo, Anthony J. (Anthony Joseph)
- Pre-trial Proceedings., February 29-May 25, 1972; (8 notebooks) (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Tuesday - February 29.
  Wednesday - March 1.
  Tuesday - April 11.
  Tuesday - April 25.
  Tuesday - May 2.
  Wednesday - May 10.
  Tuesday - May 23.
  Thursday - May 25.
- Transcripts of Trial., June 1972-May 1973; (130 vol.) (Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29)
  - June 5-June 19, 1972., (6 notebooks) (Box 2)
    Transcript Index
    vol.1: Monday, June 5 (pp.1-140).
    vol.2: Tuesday, June 6 (pp.141-317).
    vol.3: Wednesday, June 7 (pp.318-508).
    vol.4: Tuesday, June 13 (pp.509-535).
    vol.5: Monday, June 19 (pp.536-624).
  - June 20-June 28, 1972., (5 notebooks) (Box 3)
    vol.6: Tuesday, June 20 (pp.625-709).
    vol.7: Friday, June 23 (pp.710-876).
    vol.8: Monday, June 26 (pp.877-1051).
    vol.9: Tuesday, June 27 (pp.1052-1339).
    vol.10: Wednesday, June 28 (pp.1340-1554).
  - June 29-July 10, 1972., (6 notebooks) (Box 4)
    vol.11: Thursday, June 29 (pp.1555-1709).
    vol.12: Friday, June 30 (pp.1710-1714).
    vol.13: Monday, July 3 (pp.1715-1936).
    vol.14: Thursday, July 6 (pp.1937-2024).
    vol.15: Friday, July 7 (pp.2025-2190).
    vol.16: Monday, July 10 (pp.2191-2453).
  - July 11-July 14, 1972., (4 notebooks) (Box 5)
    vol.17: Tuesday, July 11 (pp.2454-2686).
    vol.18: Wednesday, July12 (pp.2687-2939).
    vol.19: Thursday, July 13 (pp.2940-3188).
    vol.20: Friday, July 14 (pp.3189-3470).
  - July 17-July 20, 1972., (4 notebooks) (Box 6)
    vol.21: Monday, July 17 (pp.3471-3690).
    vol.22: Tuesday, July 18 (pp.3691-3885).
    vol.23: Wednesday, July 19 (pp.3886-4172).
    vol.24: Thursday, July 20 (pp.4128-4404).
  - July 21-November 21, 1972., (8 notebooks) (Box 7)
    vol.25: Friday, July 21 (pp.4405-4568).
    vol.26: Monday, July 24 (pp.4569-4768).
    vol.27: Tuesday, July 25 (pp.4769-4997).
    vol.28: Wednesday, July 26 (pp.4998-5055).
    vol.29: Friday, July 28 (pp.5056-5063).
    vol.30: Monday, July 31 (pp.5064-5082).
    vol.31: Wednesday, August 9 (pp.5083-5113).
    vol.32: Tuesday, November 21 (pp.5115-5133).
  - November 30-December 20, 1972., (9 notebooks) (Box 8)
    vol.33: Thursday, November 30 (pp.5134-5293).
    vol.34: Friday, December 1 (pp.5294-5474).
    vol.35: Monday, December 4 (pp.5475-5519).
    vol.36: Wednesday, December 6 (pp.5520-5586).
    vol.37: Thursday, December 7 (pp.5587-5615).
    vol.38: Friday, December 8 (pp.5616-5653).
    vol.39: Tuesday, December 12 (pp.5654-5698).
    vol.40: Thursday, December 14 (pp.5699-5749).
    vol.41: Wednesday, December 20 (pp.5750-5859).
  - January 3-January 8, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 9)
    vol.42: Wednesday, January 3 (pp.5860-6083).
    vol.43: Thursday, January 4 (pp.6084-6323).
    vol.44: Friday, January 5 (pp.6324-6575).
    vol.45: Monday, January 8 (pp.6576-6796).
  - January 9-January 12, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 10)
    vol.46: Tuesday, January 9 (pp.6797-7025).
    vol.47: Wednesday, January 10 (pp.7026-7274).
    vol.48: Thursday, January 11 (pp.7275-7539).
    vol.49: Friday, January 12 (pp.7540-7797).
  - January 15-January 18, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 11)
    vol.50: Monday, January 15 (pp.7798-7957).
    vol.51: Tuesday, January 16 (pp.7958-8227).
    vol.52: Wednesday, January 17 (pp.8228-8426).
    vol.53: Thursday, January 18 (pp.8427-8645).
  - January 19-January 24, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 12)
    vol.54: Friday, January 19 (pp.8646-8928).
    vol.55: Monday, January 22 (pp.8929-9058).
    vol.56: Tuesday, January 23 (pp.9059-9289).
    vol.57: Wednesday, January 24 (pp.9290-9468).
  - January 26-January 31, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 13)
    vol.58: Friday, January 26 (pp.9469-9722).
    vol.59: Monday, January 29 (pp.9723-9750).
    vol.60: Tuesday, January 30 (pp.9851-10,069).
    vol.61: Wednesday, January 31 (pp.10,070-10,208).
  - February 1-February 6, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 14)
    vol.62: Thursday, February 1 (pp.10,209-10,476).
    vol.63: Friday, February 2 (pp.10,477-10,598).
    vol.64: Monday, February 5 (pp.10,599-10,837).
    vol.65: Tuesday, February 6 (pp.10,838-11,057).
  - February 7-February 12, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 15)
    vol.66: Wednesday, February 7 (pp.11,058-11,246).
    vol.67: Thursday, February 8 (pp.11,247-11,489).
    vol.68: Friday, February 9 (pp.11,490-11,733).
    vol.69: Monday, February 12 (pp.11,734-11,887).
  - February 13-February 16, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 16)
    vol.70: Tuesday, February 13 (pp.11,888-12,081).
    vol.71: Wednesday, February 14 (pp.12,082-12,265).
    vol.72: Thursday, February 15 (pp.12,266-12,505).
    vol.73: Friday, February 16 (pp.12,506-12,670).
  - February 20-February 23, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 17)
    vol.74: Tuesday, February 20 (pp.12,671-12,885).
    vol.75: Wednesday, February 21 (pp.12,886-13,088).
    vol.76: Thursday, February 22 (pp.13,089-13-230).
    vol.77: Friday, February 23 (pp.13,231-13,501).
  - February 26-March 2, 1973., (5 notebooks) (Box 18)
    vol.78: Monday, February 26 (pp.13,502-13-515).
    vol.79: Tuesday, February 27 (pp.13,516-13-708).
    vol.80: Wednesday, February 28 (pp.13,709-13,807).
    vol.81: Thursday, March 1 (pp.13,808-14,145).
    vol.82: Friday, March 2 (pp.14,146-14,378).
  - March 5-March 8, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 19)
    vol.83: Monday, March 5 (pp.14,379-14,584).
    vol.84: Tuesday, March 6 (pp.14,585-14,762).
    vol.85: Wednesday, March 7 (pp.14,764-14,962).
    vol.86: Thursday, March 8 (pp.14,963-15,151).
  - March 9-March 14, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 20)
    vol.87: Friday, March 9 (pp.15,152-15,369).
    vol.88: Monday, March 12 (pp.15,370-15,560).
    vol.89: Tuesday, March 13 (pp.15,561-15,781).
    vol.90: Wednesday, March 14 (pp.15,782-15,983).
  - March 15-March 20, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 21)
    vol.91: Thursday, March 15 (pp.15,984-16,195).
    vol.92: Friday, March 16 (pp.16,196-16,357).
    vol.93: Monday, March 19 (pp.16,358-16,477).
    vol.94: Tuesday, March 20 (pp.16,478-16,887).
  - March 21-March 27, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 22)
    vol.95: Wednesday, March 21 (pp.16,688-16,903).
    vol.96: Thursday, March 22 (pp.16,904-17,100).
    vol.97: Friday, March 23 (pp.17,101-17,336).
    vol.98: Tuesday, March 27 (pp.17,337-17,546).
  - March 28-April 2, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 23)
    vol.99: Wednesday, March 28 (pp.17,547-17,778).
    vol.100: Thursday, March 29 (pp.17,779-17,963).
    vol.101: Friday, March 30 (pp.17,964-18,197).
    vol.102: Monday, April 2 (pp.18,198-18,360).
  - April 3-April 9, 1973., (5 notebooks) (Box 24)
    vol.103: Tuesday, April 3 (pp.18,361-18,581).
    vol.104: Wednesday, April 4 (pp.18,582-18,727).
    vol.105: Thursday, April 5 (pp.18,728-18,872).
    vol.106: Friday, April 6 (pp.18,873-19,048).
    vol.107: Monday, April 9 (pp.19,049-19,223).
  - April 10-April 17, 1973., (6 notebooks) (Box 25)
    vol.108: Tuesday, April 10 (pp.19,224-19,451).
    vol.109: Wednesday, April 11 (pp.19,452-19,659).
    vol.110: Thursday, April 12 (pp.19,660-19,684).
    vol.111: Friday, April 13 (pp.19,685-19,698).
    vol.112: Monday, April 16 (pp.19,699-19,817).
    vol.113: Tuesday, April 17 (pp.19,818-20,032).
  - April 18-April 24, 1973., (5 notebooks) (Box 26)
    vol.114: Wednesday, April 18 (pp.20,033-20,186).
    vol.115: Thursday, April 19 (pp.20,187-20,413).
    vol.116: Friday, April 20 (pp.20,414-20,538).
    vol.117: Monday, April 23 (pp.20,539-20,729).
    vol.118: Tuesday, April 24 (pp.20,730-20,911).
  - April 25-May 1, 1973., (5 notebooks) (Box 27)
    vol.119: Wednesday, April 25 (pp.20,912-21,111).
    vol.120: Thursday, April 26 (pp.21,112-21,156).
    vol.121: Friday, April 27 (pp.21,157-21,330).
    vol.122: Monday, April 30 (pp.21,331-21,450).
    vol.123: Tuesday, May 1 (pp.21,451-21,642).
  - May 2-May 7, 1973., (4 notebooks) (Box 28)
    vol.124: Wednesday, May 2 (pp.21,643-21,867).
    vol.125: Thursday, May 3 (pp.21,868-22,070).
    vol.126: Friday, May 4 (pp.22,071-22,319).
    vol.127: Monday, May 7 (pp.22,320-22,389).
  - May 8-May 11, 1973., (3 notebooks) (Box 29)
    vol.128: Tuesday, May 8 (pp.22,390-22,550).
    vol.129: Thursday, May 10 (pp.22,551-22,610).
    vol.130: Friday, May 11 (pp.22,611-22,691).
- Legal Files (Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
  General note
  (Arranged in alphabetical order)
  - A - C, (6 folders) (Box 30)
    Index to Legal Files
    ACLU Amicus Briefs.
    Bekins Brief.
    Bill of Particulars.
    Constitutionality and Construction. Motion to Dismiss: Rules 8(a), 12(b).
    Appendix to Major Motion re Constitutionality and Construction.
  - D - E, (5 folders) (Box 31)
    Defendant's public Statements.
    Discovery.
    Docket Sheets.
    Electronic Surveillance.
  - E - J, (7 folders) (Box 32)
    Electronic Surveillance (Sup. Ct. Proceedings).
    Exhibit Lists.
    Gravel.
    Immunity--Russo.
    Indictment.
    Informa Pauperis.
    Jury: Grand & Petit Challenges.
  - J continued, (5 folders) (Box 33)
    Jury: Grand Jury Lists & Disclosure Proceedings.
    Jury Instructions.
    Jury: Voir Dire: Instructions to Counsel, etc.
    Supplemental Appendix to Government's Motion re Jury Selection & Instructions to Counsel.
  - L - R, (7 folders) (Box 34)
    Lack of Authorized Signature.
    Multiplicity & Duplicity.
    Prejudicial Matter.
    Protective Order.
    Protective Order (Receipts & Agreements).
    Rand Subpoena--Duces Tecum.
    Reading of Indictments.
  - R - T, (6 folders) (Box 35)
    Retaliatory Prosecution.
    Selective Prosecution.
    Severance.
    Surplusage.
    Trial Memoranda.
    Trial Miscellaneous.
  - Miscellaneous Legal Files, (7 folders) (Box 36)
    Government Subpoenas.
    Mistrial.
    Pro se.
    Government Misconduct.
    Classification Markings.
    Motion for Transfer of Trial.
  - Miscellaneous Legal Files, (4 folders) (Box 37)
    Telephone Records.
    Gag Order.
    Suppression of Evidence.
    Judgment of Acquittal.
- Exhibits (Box 38)
  Government Exhibits.
  Defense Heine Exhibits.
  Defendants' Fact Exhibits & Brady.
- Negotiations (Box 39)
  - Public Domain Material, (3 vols.). (Box 39)
  - Press Materials (Box 39)
- Press Materials (Box 40, Box 41)
  - Press, (7 folders) (Box 40)
    Background Material.
    Biographies (Defendants & Counsel).
    Biographies (Witnesses).
    Clippings, October/November/December 1972.
    Clippings, January-March, 1973.
    Clippings, April 1-May 1, 1973.
    Clippings, May 1-May 15, 1973.
  - Press, (4 folders) (Box 41)
    Releases, Letters, & Articles.
    Photos (incomplete set).
    Summary of prosecution Case.
    Weekly Summaries.
- Witness Books, Exhibits 1-18 (Box 42, Box 43, Box 44)
  - Exhibits 1-8, (8 notebooks) (Box 42)
    Exhibit 1: vol.I--Vietnam and the U.S., 1940-1950.
    Exhibit 2: vol.II--U.S. Involvement in the Franco-Viet Minh War.
    Exhibit 3: vol.IV.A.Z: id for France in Indochina.
    Exhibit 4: vol.IV-U.S. and France's Withdrawal from Vietnam, 1954-1956.
    Exhibit 5: vol.IV.A.4--U.S. Training of the Vietnamese National Army, 1954-1959.
    Exhibit 6: vol.IV.A.5--The Origins of the Insurgency.
    Exhibit 7: vol.II.B.2--Strategic Hamlet Program, 1961-1963.
    Exhibit 8: vol.IV.B.4--Phases Withdrawal of U.S. Forces,1962-1964.
  - Exhibits 9-15, (7 notebooks) (Box 43)
    Exhibit 9: vol.IV.B.5--The Overthrow of Ngo Dinh Diem, May-November 1963.
    Exhibit 10: vol.IV.C.4--Marine Combat Units go to Danang.
    Exhibit 11: vol.IV.C.5--Phase I in the Build-up of U.S. Forces: March-July 1965.
    Exhibit 12: vol.IV.C.8--Re-emphasis on pacification, 1965-1967.
    Exhibit 13: vol.IV.C.9(a)--U.S./GVN Relations: 1963-1967.
    Exhibit 14: vol.IV.C.9(b)--U.S./GVN Relations: July 1965-December 1967.
    Exhibit 15: vol.IV.C.1--History of Contacts: 1965-1966.
  - Exhibits 16-18, (4 notebooks) (Box 44)
    Exhibit 16 (Government): vol.VI.C.2--History of Contacts: Polish Track (Marigold).
    Exhibit 17 (Government): vol.VI.C.3--History of Contacts: Moscow-London Track (Sunflower).
    Exhibit 18 (Government): vol.VI.C.4-History of Contacts, 1967-1968.
    Exhibits 15-18 (Government): Histories of Contacts, General Material.